Thomas Lowe Hughes Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Correspondence, 1943-2006 (Box 94-127)
  Arranged into three groupings: Alphabetical file, Chronological file, and Special signatures, and arranged alphabetically or chronologically therein.
  - Alphabetical file (Box 94)
    - Andrew Carnegie Sesquicentennial Gathering, 1985 (Box 94)
    - "A" miscellaneous, 1960-1998, undated, (4 folders) (Box 94)
    - Benitez, Margarita, 1996-1997 (Box 94)
    - Bernstein, Merton C., 1991-1992 (Box 95)
    - Birnbaum, Norman, 1979-1991 (Box 95)
    - Bowles, Chester, Yale University Lecture Series, 1981-1987 (Box 95)
    - "B" miscellaneous, 1952-1997, undated, (10 folders) (Box 95)
    - Cabán, Angel, 1982 (Box 96)
    - Carleton College, Northfield, Minn., 1957-1991, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - Carleton College Board of Trustees, 1958, 1988-1995 (Box 96)
    - "C" miscellaneous, 1954-1998, undated, (6 folders) (Box 96)
    - Dillon, Wilton S., 1990-1996 (Box 96)
    - Dulles, John F., memorial programs, 1986-1990 (Box 96)
    - Dulles, John F., memorial programs, 1986-1990 (Box 97)
    - "D" miscellaneous, 1954-1998, undated, (5 folders) (Box 97)
    - "E" miscellaneous, 1954-1996, (3 folders) (Box 97)
    - Fabian, Larry L., 1993-1996 (Box 97)
    - Fonseca, Rena, 1991 (Box 97)
    - Foster, Robert, 1984-1992 (Box 97)
    - "F" miscellaneous, 1957-1997, (4 folders) (Box 98)
    - Gandía, Margarita, 1946, 1976-1977 (Box 98)
    - Ginsburg, Feldman, and Bress Ginsburg, 1975-1977 (Box 98)
    - "G" miscellaneous, 1954-1997, undated, (5 folders) (Box 98)
    - Halperin, Morton H., 1969 (Box 98)
    - Heuven, Marten van, 1992-1994 (Box 98)
    - Hilsman, Ashby, 1996 (Box 99)
    - Holbrooke, Richard C., 1979-1997 (Box 99)
    - Hughes, Jean, 1959 (Box 99)
    - "H" miscellaneous, 1953-1995, (9 folders) (Box 99)
    - "H" miscellaneous, 1996-1998, undated (Box 100)
    - "I" miscellaneous, 1958, 1964-1968, 1990-1998 (Box 100)
    - "J" miscellaneous, 1954-1995, undated, (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Katz, Milton, 1995 (Box 100)
    - King, Kay, Association of Professional Schools of International Affairs, 1998 (Box 100)
    - "K" miscellaneous, 1953-1996, undated, (6 folders) (Box 100)
    - "L" miscellaneous, 1954-1971, (3 folders) (Box 100)
    - "L" miscellaneous, 1972-1996, undated, (4 folders) (Box 101)
    - Mathews, Jessica Tuchman, 1993-1998 (Box 101)
    - Maynes, Charles, 1992-1997 (Box 101)
    - "M" miscellaneous, 1954-1976, (5 folders) (Box 101)
    - "M" miscellaneous, 1977-2001, undated, (4 folders) (Box 102)
    - Nelson, Daniel, 1990-1997 (Box 102)
    - "N" miscellaneous, 1952-1997, undated, (3 folders) (Box 102)
    - Omestad, Thomas, 1994-1997 (Box 102)
    - "O" miscellaneous, 1954-1995, undated, (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - Personal friends and family, 1981-1991 (Box 102)
    - Personal friends and family, 1981-1991, (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - Pickus, Robert, 1970-1974 (Box 103)
    - "P" miscellaneous, 1954-1998, undated, (4 folders) (Box 103)
    - "R" miscellaneous, 1952-1974, (4 folders) (Box 103)
    - "R" miscellaneous, 1977-1997, undated, (4 folders) (Box 104)
    - Schever, Steven, 1954-1972 (Box 104)
    - Shapley, Deborah, 1989-1991 (Box 104)
    - Steel, Ronald, 1994 (Box 104)
    - Sturua, M. G., 1991-1993 (Box 104)
    - "S" miscellaneous, 1944-1976, (6 folders) (Box 104)
    - "S" miscellaneous, 1977-1998, undated, (5 folders) (Box 105)
    - Talbott, Strobe, 1994 (Box 105)
    - "T" miscellaneous, 1954-1997, undated, (3 folders) (Box 105)
    - United Nations, 1985-1992 (Box 105)
    - "U" miscellaneous, 1960-1995, (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - "V" miscellaneous, 1947-1997, undated, (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - Weinshall, Theodore D., 1971 (Box 105)
    - White, Barbara, 1972 (Box 105)
    - "W" miscellaneous, 1946, 1953-1958 (Box 105)
    - "W" miscellaneous, 1959-1998, undated, (6 folders) (Box 106)
    - Yale University, 1967-1977, 1985-1990 (Box 106)
    - "Y" miscellaneous, 1956-1997, undated, (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - "Z" miscellaneous, 1961-1968, 1979, 1987-1996, undated, (2 folders) (Box 106)
  - Chronological file, 1945-1962, (12 folders) (Box 106)
  - Chronological file, 1963-1973, (13 folders) (Box 107)
  - Chronological file, 1974-1979, (7 folders) (Box 108)
  - Chronological file, 1980-1983, (8 folders) (Box 109)
  - Chronological file, 1983-1985, (8 folders) (Box 110)
  - Chronological file, 1985-1986, (7 folders) (Box 111)
  - Chronological file, 1987-1988, (7 folders) (Box 112)
  - Chronological file, 1989-1990, (7 folders) (Box 113)
  - Chronological file, 1990-1993, (9 folders) (Box 114)
  - Chronological file, 1994-1998, (10 folders) (Box 115)
  - Chronological file, 1999-2007, (10 folders) (Box 116)
  - Chronological file, 2008-2017, undated, (10 folders) (Box 117)
  - Special signatures (Box 117)
    - Africa, 1971-1997 (Box 117)
    - Anderson, Eugenie M., 1944-1964, 1997, (2 folders) (Box 117)
    - Annenberg, Walter H., 1969-1985 (Box 117)
    - Asia, 1961-1992 (Box 117)
    - Atkeson, Timothy B., 1953-1990 (Box 117)
    - Australia and New Zealand, 1963-1993 (Box 117)
    - Ball, George, 1967-1986 (Box 117)
    - Ball, Joseph H., 1944-1948 (Box 117)
    - Battle, Lucius D., and Betty Battle, 1964-1989 (Box 117)
    - Bennet, Douglas J., 1963-1974 (Box 117)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, 1972-1984 (Box 117)
    - Bolté, Charles G., 1964-1986 (Box 117)
    - Bowles, Chester, 1955-1959 (Box 117)
    - British conferences, 1985-1990 (Box 117)
    - Bussche, Axel von dem, 1981-1993, (2 folders) (Box 118)
    - Cabinet officers, 1962-1996 (Box 118)
    - Canada, 1965-1995 (Box 118)
    - Celebrities and officials, 1944-1996, 2003, (3 folders) (Box 118)
    - Celebrities and officials, 1944-1996, 2003, (7 folders) (Box 119)
    - Celebrities and officials, 1944-1996, 2003 (Box 120)
    - Celeste, Richard F., 1968-1986 (Box 120)
    - Central and South America, 1964-1992 (Box 120)
    - Chayes, Abram, 1955-1967, 1987 (Box 120)
    - Cleveland, Harlan, 1966-1988 (Box 120)
    - Colón, Rafel Hernández, 1967-1993, 2003 (Box 120)
    - Dungan, Ralph A., 1959-1965 (Box 120)
    - Durning, Marvin B., 1952-1973 (Box 120)
    - England, 1947-1998, (4 folders) (Box 120)
    - England, 1947-1998, (3 folders) (Box 121)
    - Erickson, John, 1952-1963 (Box 121)
    - European meetings and conferences, 1957-1998, (2 folders) (Box 121)
    - Ferré, Luis Alberto, 1967-1969 (Box 121)
    - Germany, 1948, 1953-2008, (3 folders) (Box 121)
    - Germany, 1948, 1953-2008 (Box 122)
    - Gould, Laurence M., 1954-1981 (Box 122)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, 1967-1991 (Box 122)
    - Hilsman, Roger, 1963-1977, circa 1990 (Box 122)
    - Hitchcock, William, 1962-1972, 1984 (Box 122)
    - Hoopes, Townsend, 1966-1974, 2002 (Box 122)
    - Howard, Frances, 1966-1993 (Box 122)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1957-1989 (Box 122)
    - India, 1958-1993 (Box 122)
    - Intelligence officials, 1962-1997, (2 folders) (Box 122)
    - International organizations, 1972-1994 (Box 123)
    - Israel, 1956-1994 (Box 123)
    - Jonas, Gilbert, 1958-1973 (Box 123)
    - Journalists and columnists, 1945, 1960-1996, (3 folders) (Box 123)
    - Judicial officials, 1945, 1961-1989 (Box 123)
    - Kaiser, Philip M., 1963-1998 (Box 123)
    - Kampelman, Max M., 1954-1990 (Box 123)
    - Katzenbach, Nicholas deB., 1962-1968, 1988 (Box 123)
    - Kenen, Isaiah "Si", 1961-1969 (Box 123)
    - Kennan, George, 1965-1968, 1980 (Box 124)
    - Kennedy family, 1960-1988 (Box 124)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1965-1976 (Box 124)
    - Knopp, Werner, 1985-1997 (Box 124)
    - Lang, Rex, 1945-1971 (Box 124)
    - Lathem, Willoughby, 1961-1970 (Box 124)
    - Lowenstein, Allard K., 1969, 1984-1985, 1993 (Box 124)
    - Middle East, 1978-1984, 1990 (Box 124)
    - McCarthy, Eugene, 1954-1978, 1996 (Box 124)
    - Mondale, Walter F., 1973-2006 (Box 124)
    - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1969-1977, 1985, 1994 (Box 124)
    - Nash, John, 1962-1969, 1991 (Box 124)
    - Nason, John W., 1954, 1962-1991 (Box 124)
    - Nolte, Richard H., 1964-1984 (Box 124)
    - Polk, William R., 1966-1968 (Box 124)
    - Puerto Rico, 1972-1996 (Box 124)
    - Richardson, Elliot L., 1969-1990 (Box 124)
    - Rieke, Robert, 1954-1996 (Box 124)
    - Rivkin, Donald H., 1954-1978 (Box 124)
    - Rockefeller, David, 1969-1991 (Box 125)
    - Ross and Haines, Inc., 1969-1971 (Box 125)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1961-1989 (Box 125)
    - Samuel, Daniel, 1980-1990 (Box 125)
    - Scheuer, Steven, 1960-1968, 1977 (Box 125)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr., 1962-1983 (Box 125)
    - Secretaries of state, 1956, 1966-1997 (Box 125)
    - Sihanouk, Norodom, 1962, 1980-1988 (Box 125)
    - Staden, Berndt von, and Wendi von Staden, 1964-2001 (Box 125)
    - Staff, Senate Committee on Foreign Relations and House Committee on Foreign Affairs, 1959-1989 (Box 125)
    - Stassen, Harold E., 1943-1948 (Box 125)
    - Stern, Fritz, 1976-1990, 1998 (Box 125)
    - Thomson, James, Jr., 1961-1972 (Box 125)
    - United States ambassadors, 1959-1998, (2 folders) (Box 125)
    - United States ambassadors, 1959-1998, (8 folders) (Box 126)
    - United States congressional representatives, 1945, 1957-1995, 2006, (2 folders) (Box 126)
    - United States presidents, 1952-1975, 1992-1996 (Box 127)
    - United States senators, 1945-1992, (4 folders) (Box 127)
    - Washington Institute of Foreign Affairs, 1990-1998, 2006, (2 folders) (Box 127)
    - Watt, David, 1978-1989 (Box 127)
    - Weizsäcker, Richard von, 1977-1994, 2002 (Box 127)
    - Whiting, Allen, 1962-1974, 1994 (Box 127)
    - Williams, Murat W., 1964-1986 (Box 127)
- Speeches and Writings, 1955-2017 (Box 128-153)
  The Speeches and Writing series contains transcripts of speeches Hughes gave at a variety of professional and personal engagements, articles, and an extensive collection of notes pertaining to speech and article ideas, meetings, and other professional matters. The speeches in this series span the years 1954-2007 and represent engagements in which Hughes participated while working for the Department of State's Bureau of Intelligence and Research and for the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace as president and president emeritus. The majority of the speeches are arranged chronologically, with some arranged topically for specific functions where Hughes spoke regularly, namely Mid-Atlantic Club meetings, Carnegie Endowment Board of Trustees meetings, and gatherings of the Oxford-Cambridge Association. The writings in this series are largely article adaptations of Hughes’s speeches published in Foreign Affairs magazine. Also included is material chronicling a preface Hughes wrote for the Bureau of Intelligence and Research’s Vietnam study after it was declassified in 2004. The notes in this series are extensive and cover a wide variety of topics ranging from personal and professional meetings, to impressions of projects, colleagues, and current events, and ideas for article and speech content. Hughes's notes are filed across the collection in multiple series. Other series with significant notes include the Department of State, Bureau of Intelligence and Research file and Carnegie Endowment for Intentional Peace Subject file.
  - Articles, 1959-1974, (5 folders) (Box 128)
  - Articles, 1975-1991, (4 folders) (Box 129)
  - Articles, 1992-2003, 2012, (3 folders) (Box 130)
  - Notes (Box 130)
    - 5,000 vs. 5 million, oppositionism, 1983 (Box 130)
    - Amazing Grace Task Force, Jimmy Carter, 1978 (Box 130)
    - American politics and culture, 1983 (Box 130)
    - Article material, circa 1980s, (2 folders) (Box 130)
    - Article material, circa 1980s (Box 131)
    - Bilderberg meeting, Knokke-Heist, Belgium, 1972 (Box 131)
    - "Broadening reputations: People the inscrutable liberal," undated (Box 131)
    - Buchanan, Scott; Toynbee seminar, 1955-1958 (Box 131)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1973-1983 (Box 131)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace reports, 1970-1979, (2 folders) (Box 131)
    - CBS Show, Poland, 1981-12-29, 1981 December 29 (Box 131)
    - Chronological file, 1960-1972, (5 folders) (Box 131)
    - Chronological file, 1973-1986, (9 folders) (Box 132)
    - Chronological file, 1987-1999, (9 folders) (Box 133)
    - Chronological file, 1999-2017, undated, (10 folders) (Box 134)
    - Classification, 1971-1972 (Box 134)
    - Colby, William, 2011 (Box 134)
    - Commitments, assurances, intentions, loopholes, negotiation tactics, 1974 (Box 134)
    - Conversations, Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1970-1971 (Box 135)
    - Conversations, important, 1970-1987 (Box 135)
    - Counterinsurgency, 1968 (Box 135)
    - "The Crack Up," 1980, (2 folders) (Box 135)
    - Détente, 1974 (Box 135)
    - Development, 1970 (Box 135)
    - German Democratic Republic, report, 1989 (Box 135)
    - German issues, 1982 (Box 135)
    - Germany, 2005 (Box 135)
    - Germany, Leo von Caprivi, 1974 (Box 135)
    - "Goodbye Liberalism Forever," 1968 (Box 135)
    - Humor, 1964-1989, (4 folders) (Box 136)
    - Intelligence, C.I.A., Congress, 1994 (Box 137)
    - Intern lunch, 1989 (Box 137)
    - International interest, 1967 (Box 137)
    - International mind, reputation, circa 1970 (Box 137)
    - Introductions of speakers, 1978-1981 (Box 137)
    - Iraq, 2002 (Box 137)
    - Johnson, Joseph E., 1970-1972 (Box 137)
    - Katz, Milton, 1970-1972 (Box 137)
    - Korea (conference), 2008 (Box 137)
    - Liberals, 1968-1970, 1983 (Box 137)
    - Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 137)
    - Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 138)
    - Muskie, Edmund S., 1970-1972 (Box 138)
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1968-1985 (Box 138)
    - "On being out of Phrase: Affinities, people," undated (Box 138)
    - Oxford, England, 1969-1977 (Box 138)
    - Palestine, 1976 (Box 138)
    - Personnel files, 1985-1991 (Box 138)
    - Populism and Minnesota, 1975 (Box 138)
    - Prados, John, 2006 (Box 138)
    - Porter, Gareth, 2002-2006 (Box 138)
    - "Power of negative thinking," undated (Box 138)
    - Reagan, Ronald, unused article material, 1981 (Box 138)
    - Shriver for President Committee, 1975 (Box 138)
    - Speech material, 1960-1989, (3 folders) (Box 139)
    - Speech material, 1988 (Box 140)
    - Tann, Caroline von der, 1977 (Box 140)
    - Transition, 1976 (Box 140)
    - United Kingdom, Europe, NATO, 1968-1970 (Box 140)
    - Watergate, intelligence, wiretaps, 1973-1974 (Box 140)
    - White House briefing, Malta Summit, 1989 (Box 140)
    - Yale Law School, 1965-1979 (Box 140)
  - Speeches
    - Board of Trustees meetings, 1971-1990, (2 folders) (Box 140)
    - Chronological, 1954-1966, (2 folders) (Box 140)
    - Chronological, 1967-1969, (5 folders) (Box 141)
    - Chronological, 1969-1973, (4 folders) (Box 142)
    - Chronological, 1973-1975, (4 folders) (Box 143)
    - Chronological, 1975-1977, (4 folders) (Box 144)
    - Chronological, 1978-1982, (4 folders) (Box 145)
    - Chronological, 1984-1990, (6 folders) (Box 146)
    - Chronological, 1991-1997, (7 folders) (Box 147)
    - Chronological, 1998-2007, (4 folders) (Box 148)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1971-1981 (Box 148)
    - Index, circa 2000 (Box 148)
    - Law school, 1984 (Box 148)
    - Mid-Atlantic Club, 1977-1998, (2 folders) (Box 148)
    - Oxford-Cambridge Association, 1965-1999, (2 folders) (Box 149)
  - Vietnam study preface
    - Correspondence, 1990-2005, (4 folders) (Box 149)
    - Final preface, 2004 (Box 149)
    - "Kennedy, Johnson, and Vietnam," conference, 2003-2009 (Box 149)
    - "Kennedy, Johnson, and Vietnam," conference, 2003-2009, (3 folders) (Box 150)
    - Lyndon Baines Johnson Library, Vietnam roundtable, 1991-1993, (3 folders) (Box 150)
    - Lyndon Baines Johnson Library, Vietnam roundtable, 1991-1993 (Box 151)
    - McNamara, Robert S., 1983-1997, (4 folders) (Box 151)
    - Notes, 1990-2007 (Box 151)
    - Notes, 1990-2007, (4 folders) (Box 152)
    - Original Bureau of Intelligence and Research Vietnam study, 1969, 2004, (2 folders) (Box 152)
    - Original Bureau of Intelligence and Research Vietnam study, 1969, 2004, (3 folders) (Box 153)
    - Research materials, 1962-2005, (3 folders) (Box 153)
- Boards and Associations, 1967-2013 (Box 154-186)
  The Boards and Associations series documents Hughes’s involvement with various international affairs think tanks and nongovernmental organizations. Hughes served on the boards of several institutions that aimed to conduct foreign policy research and to strengthen diplomatic relations between the United States and its Western allies. Several of these boards and associations specifically focus on United States-German relations. Major topics include the global economy, German reunification, international security and defense, the recruitment and selection of new board members, fundraising and grants, and logistics for meetings, conferences, and lectures.
  Material types include correspondence, meeting minutes, notes, reports, conference programs, and clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically by organization name.
  - American Academy in Berlin, 1994-1996, (4 folders) (Box 154)
  - American Academy in Berlin, 1997-1999, (3 folders) (Box 155)
  - American Academy in Berlin, 1999-2000, (4 folders) (Box 156)
  - American Academy in Berlin, 2001-2005 (Box 157)
  - American Council on Germany, 1971-1991, (2 folders) (Box 157)
  - American Ditchley Foundation, 1971-1977, (2 folders) (Box 157)
  - American Ditchley Foundation, 1980-1992, (2 folders) (Box 158)
  - American Institute for Contemporary German Studies, 1985-1989, (2 folders) (Box 158)
  - American Institute for Contemporary German Studies, 1989-1990, (3 folders) (Box 159)
  - American Institute for Contemporary German Studies, 1990-1992, (3 folders) (Box 160)
  - American Institute for Contemporary German Studies, 1992-1994, (4 folders) (Box 161)
  - American Institute for Contemporary German Studies, 1994-1996, (4 folders) (Box 162)
  - American Institute for Contemporary German Studies, 1997-2009, (4 folders) (Box 163)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States, 1971-1982, (4 folders) (Box 164)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States, 1983-1990, (4 folders) (Box 165)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States, 1990-1992, (4 folders) (Box 166)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States, 1993-1997, (4 folders) (Box 167)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States, 1998-2002 (Box 168)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies, 1988-1992, (2 folders) (Box 168)
  - Council for Puerto Rico, 1987 (Box 168)
  - Council for Puerto Rico, 1988-1989, (3 folders) (Box 169)
  - Council for Puerto Rico, 1989-1994, (3 folders) (Box 170)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1967-1970 (Box 170)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1971-1977, (4 folders) (Box 171)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1978-1989, (5 folders) (Box 172)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1990-2005, (4 folders) (Box 173)
  - Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung, 1982-1998 (Box 173)
  - German Historical Institute, 1987-2002 (Box 173)
  - German Marshall Fund (Box 174)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1979, (3 folders) (Box 174)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1992, (2 folders) (Box 175)
    - European-American and International Issues Panel, 1980-1981 (Box 175)
    - General, 1967-1998 (Box 175)
    - General, 1967-1998, (3 folders) (Box 176)
    - General, 1967-1998 (Box 177)
    - Goldman, Guido, 1971-1972, 2012-2013, (4 folders) (Box 177)
    - International Problems Review Conference, 1978 (Box 177)
    - International Writers Service, 1976-1978 (Box 178)
    - Lists, 1975-1979 (Box 178)
    - Marshall Memorial Convocation, 1972 (Box 178)
    - Marshall Plan Memorial Lecture Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 178)
    - Meetings, 1972-1981, (2 folders) (Box 178)
    - Meetings, 1972-1981 (Box 179)
    - Policy Studies Institute/Istituto Affari Internazionali Project, 1979-1980 (Box 179)
    - Presidential searches, 1972-1981, 1994-1995, (2 folders) (Box 179)
    - Trustee selection, 1977-1980, (2 folders) (Box 180)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1998-1999 (Box 180)
  - International Institute for Strategic Studies, 1968-1979, (2 folders) (Box 180)
  - International Institute for Strategic Studies, 1980-1984, (4 folders) (Box 181)
  - International Institute for Strategic Studies, 1985-1990, (5 folders) (Box 182)
  - International Institute for Strategic Studies, 1991-1999, 2007, (4 folders) (Box 183)
  - Konrad-Adenauer-Stiftung, 1990-1998 (Box 184)
  - Nuclear Proliferation and Safeguards Advisory Panel, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 184)
  - Trilateral Commission, 1973-1975, (2 folders) (Box 184)
  - Trilateral Commission, 1976-1998, (4 folders) (Box 185)
  - Washington Institute of Foreign Affairs, 1997-2005 (Box 186)
- Personal File, 1918-2017 (Box 186-200)
  The Personal File contains material related to Hughes’s education, military service, and endeavors outside of his later professional career. Correspondence written and received by Hughes while an undergraduate at Carleton College (1943-1947), a Rhodes Scholar at Balliol College, University of Oxford (1947-1949), law student at Yale Law School (1949-1952), and lieutenant in the Air Force (1953-1954) comprises the majority of the series. Major topics include Hughes’s involvement with the Student Federalists movement, especially as national president from 1944 to 1945, travels around Europe in the postwar period, work with the Foundation for World Government in ʻEn ha-Shofeṭ, Israel, in the summer of 1950, and early work as a law student with the Senate Subcommittee on Labor and Labor Management Relations in the summer of 1951. Letters across the series feature Hughes's parents, Evan Raymond Hughes and Alice Lowe Hughes, friends, and contacts from the Student Federalists movement. The correspondence in this series was maintained as received and is organized by institution with which Hughes was affiliated or location at which he resided at a given time. Researchers should note that many topics and correspondents, namely contacts associated with the Student Federalists movement, are spread across the series. Researchers should also consult the General Correspondence file, as relevant correspondence from Hughes’s pre-career years is included, though to a limited degree.
  Material types include correspondence, photographs, military papers, and printed material.
  - Air Force (Box 186)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1953, (5 folders) (Box 186)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1954, (2 folders) (Box 187)
    - General, 1952-1967 (Box 187)
    - Reserves, 1957-1967, (3 folders) (Box 187)
    - Visits (Box 187)
      - Copenhagen, Denmark, 1959 (Box 187)
      - Europe, 1957, 1963, (2 folders) (Box 187)
      - Florida, California, New Mexico, 1960 (Box 187)
      - Hawaii, Japan, Alaska, Guam, Philippines, Thailand, 1961 (Box 187)
      - Hawaii, Japan, Alaska, Guam, Philippines, Thailand, 1961 (Box 188)
      - London, England, 1963 (Box 188)
      - Madrid, Spain, 1963 (Box 188)
  - Autobiographical notes, undated (Box 188)
  - Autobiography (age 13), 1939 (Box 188)
  - Awards, 1965, 1968 (Box 188)
  - Biographical summaries and résumés, 1960-2002, (2 folders) (Box 188)
  - Carleton College, Northfield, Minn. (Box 188)
    - Clippings, 1943-1947, (3 folders) (Box 188)
    - Conferences and panels (general), 1944-1947 (Box 189)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1945, (6 folders) (Box 189)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1947, (7 folders) (Box 190)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 191)
    - Debate, 1944-1947 (Box 191)
    - Democratic National Convention, Chicago, Ill., 1944, (3 folders) (Box 191)
    - Enright, Adelaide, 1944-1946 (Box 191)
    - Gould, Laurence McKinley, inauguration, 1945 (Box 191)
    - Kerr, Florence, 1946-1947 (Box 191)
    - Kiefer, Alois, 1943-1947 (Box 191)
    - Leadership institutes, 1943-1945 (Box 191)
    - Oratory, 1943-1946 (Box 192)
    - Photographs, 1943-1947 (Box 192)
    - Student Federalist (newspaper), 1944-1946 (Box 192)